<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Saurav Singh</title>
		<description>Personal Blog</description>		
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>EuroPython And A Lot More Awesomeness</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey Guys, Im pleased to tell you that I will be travelling to Italy on 2nd week of July. Im very excited about it as this would be my first foreign trip. There I will attending EuroPython’17 Conference along with my other admins/mentors of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coala&lt;/code&gt;. This is gonna be a long post so get ready for awesomeness!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-exactly-is-europython-and-why-am-i-attending-it&quot;&gt;What exactly is EuroPython and why am I attending it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroPython is a community initiative by a team of Python enthusiast in Europe to bring together Python users and developers, as well as provide an opportunity for those who are interested in these technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So around march &lt;em&gt;Lasse&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/sils&quot;&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt;) invited us all for this conference where since past 2 years was the venue for coalians annual meet. Although I haven’t spent a lot of time with these guys. But now it feels like I have been knowing them since years and hence, I will really be pleased to meet them all. Even my mentor of GSoC’17 &lt;em&gt;Niklas&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/NiklasMM&quot;&gt;@NiklasMM&lt;/a&gt; will be present. Yes my dream of having a beer with my mentor is coming true :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to share that I had applied for a Talk proposal on the words of my admins. Though it got rejected but Im happy. I have never been to a Tech. conference before, so I was a bit hesitant about it. But If I will get a chance surely I will give a lightening talk about my GSoC project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;funding-and-sponsorship&quot;&gt;Funding and Sponsorship.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes guys you have read it perfectly I m being funded for this trip. Though not fully but partially and I m really thankful to the guys who are helping me to actually make this affordable. First of all Thanks to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Kiwi.com&lt;/code&gt; for their generosity and their amazing programme source-lift which funds open-source teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-source-lift-programme&quot;&gt;What is source-lift programme?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/kiwidotcom_source_lift.png&quot; alt=&quot;kiwidotcom source lift&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kiwi.com is giving away flights to open source teams that need to travel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can say it in one sentence. It’s their way of thanking to the world of FOSS. Source-lift programme funds Open-Source organizations to make their dream of attending a conference together come true. They do so by providing each member of the team with flight voucher upto 200 Euros. Read more about them on their official site: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kiwi.com/sourcelift/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kiwi.com/sourcelift&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coala&lt;/code&gt; is the first organization to be a part this programme. It’s was the effort of &lt;em&gt;Lasse&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/sils&quot;&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt;) and few other admins to make this happen. Im really Thankful to them for such an effort. Keep bringing more awesomeness to the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/kiwidotcom_coala.png&quot; alt=&quot;kiwidotcom coala&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Guys here’s how the voucher looks like :) It gives me chills thinking that I m one of the first few members to get this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/kiwidotcom_mail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kiwidotcom mail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I have heard that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/code&gt; funded some of the GSoC students last year. There haven’t been any official news about it for this year so far. And that’s what worried me mostly. But &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kiwi.com&lt;/code&gt; made my thought clear that I would be definitely attending &lt;strong&gt;EP’2017&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks again guys!! You’re Awesome.
So, I am all set, applied for a VISA. Hopefully It will get accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all people. Till my next blog see yaa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/EuroPython-And-A-Lot-More-Awesomeness.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/EuroPython-And-A-Lot-More-Awesomeness.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Phase 1 Mid Month Summary</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there Guys!, I hope you are doing well. In this blog I will summarizing my GSoC’17 work till now. So it’s been 18 days of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Coding Phase-I&lt;/code&gt; and I have been moving forward with all I have, to make this project come to life. So Let’s begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since, I learnt my lesson well from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bonding Phase&lt;/code&gt; :P so I started solving the big issues first. As they takes up a lot of time in review phase. Firstly I began adding additional functionalities to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationComment&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationComment&lt;/code&gt; is the core of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationAPI&lt;/code&gt; which mainly dissociated the whole documentation into it’s sub-parts (i.e. params,exceptions and return descriptions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Previous &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;assemble()&lt;/code&gt; function was not accounting for a case in which middle and ending markers are same. Eg. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;marker[1]==marker[2]&lt;/code&gt; which is a type of case in python docstring.
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;docstring_find&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;filename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;## This is dummy docstring find function.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#  @param filename contains filename&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#  @raises FileNotFoundError raises when filename is not found&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#  @return nothing&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hence I completed the work over this and a patch is submitted and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala/pull/4319&quot;&gt;merged&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationComment&lt;/code&gt; accepts &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;range&lt;/code&gt; as an argument we will be shifting it to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;position&lt;/code&gt;. Since &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TextRange&lt;/code&gt; is constructed from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TextPosition&lt;/code&gt; it’s just a simplification of constructor but important indeed. A patch is currectly in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala/issues/2646&quot;&gt;review phase&lt;/a&gt; right now. I guess it will be merged in 2 review iterations or so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these were the two major changes which I had done, making about 60% completion of the milestones in my opinion. I guess this time I will be able to achieve 100%. 100% or not my patches should be good in quality thats my inner objective ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one more thing, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala-bears/pull/1506&quot;&gt;big patch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationStyleBear&lt;/code&gt; finally got accepted. It’s not fully complete at the moment. Requires lot of additional functionalities but that’s the basic functionality which we have longed for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-up-ahead&quot;&gt;What’s up ahead?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I have 4 additions lined up for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationExtraction&lt;/code&gt; out of which only 2 are solvable at the moment and the rest will be moved ahead to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Coding Phase-II&lt;/code&gt;. I will be writing more about them in my next blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all guys. Till next time See YAA!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/Phase-1-Mid-Month-Summary.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/Phase-1-Mid-Month-Summary.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Bonding Period Ends</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Guys!! With the end of this month &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Community Bonding&lt;/code&gt; period finally comes to an end, which marks the beginning of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Coding Phase-I&lt;/code&gt;. In which, students officially now starts coding on their projects. Before even I would start with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Coding Phase-I&lt;/code&gt;, I thought about summarizing my overall objectives achieved in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Community Bonding&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started with testing the old &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationStyleBear&lt;/code&gt; over &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coala&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coala-bears&lt;/code&gt; repo. My first task was to get the old &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala-bears/pull/1506&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocStyleBear&lt;/code&gt; PR&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SanketDG&quot;&gt;SanketDG&lt;/a&gt; merged, currently! I have hijacked it :P . I found 2 major issues while testing:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We know python has some fancy strings which are written as:
        &lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;arguments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;
sum= a+b+c
avg= (a+b+c)/3
&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentionAPI&lt;/code&gt; should ignore such strings. I had a healthy discussion with my mentors about this issue and we came to a conclusion that it required some more ideation, hence being moved to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Coding Phase-I&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationAPI&lt;/code&gt; was not having support for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:raises xyz:&lt;/code&gt;. Hence, it’s being successfully &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala/pull/4281&quot;&gt;implemented&lt;/a&gt;. The patch right now is in review phase.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There was bug in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocumentationAPI&lt;/code&gt;, which generated cut-off diffs. For example, if a docstring is written this way:
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;
 This is not a cool way to write docstrings.
    &quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The generated diff would be.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;
     not a cool way to write docstrings.
    &quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A patch fixing this bug has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala/pull/4275&quot;&gt;implemented and merged&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new parameter &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;allow_missing_func_desc&lt;/code&gt; needs to be added which will ignore a warning message, when &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DocStyleBear&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t finds a function description. This has also been &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala-bears/pull/1506&quot;&gt;implemented&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Last and Final task was to analyze coala’s structure and write a blog about it. So, &lt;a href=&quot;https://damngamerz.github.io/gsoc/An-Insight-Into-coala's-Structure.html&quot;&gt;here it is&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end here’s a burnout chart depicting my working efficiency.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/chart_bonding.png&quot; alt=&quot;bonding chart&quot; /&gt;
Although, I wasn’t able to complete my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bonding&lt;/code&gt; milestone 100%. As to close an issue, the related PR should be merged beforehand. While I got my 2 PR’s in review state. And both of those PR’s had big updates/patches, which I submitted beforehand deadline by 2 days and hence it didn’t got sufficient time to go through review phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Coding Phase-I&lt;/code&gt; begins now, and I can’t risk my chances of staying behind schedule. The things I learned from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Community Bonding&lt;/code&gt; phase will play a very crucial role in this phase, one of which is I have to submit my patches as early as possible, cause about 60% time goes in review cycle. Ofcourse, I don’t blame the review process by that statement, cause it is very fruitful and it always polishes the PR to get merge ready. Although, I must say coala’s review process is fast, well faster than the other open-source organisations, In which a simple patch can be in review phase for months before it finally gets accepted. Here it take a day or so. But for big patches it obviously takes weeks of review iterations to actually get it merged. Kudos!! to all my fellow devs and maintainers for making this process fast!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special Thanks to both of my mentors &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SanketDG&quot;&gt;SanketDG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NiklasMM&quot;&gt;NiklasMM&lt;/a&gt; and other mentors of coala. Without them this wouldn’t have been possible. Thanks for understanding when I asked to code in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bonding Period&lt;/code&gt; phase and making me code in, which really gave me a taste of how &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Coding Phase-I&lt;/code&gt; will actually go. I will try hard to not let you guys down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till next time Tschüss!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/Bonding-Period-Ends.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/Bonding-Period-Ends.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>An Insight Into coala's Structure</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Guys!! Its been a long since my last post. This blog post is intended for all newcomer’s who would like to contribute to coala. So, I will give you an insight into coala’s Structure in a bit detail to actually get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-insight-into-coalas-structure&quot;&gt;An Insight Into coala’s Structure.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;coala’s code base can be found here at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. It’s directory tree looks like:
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/coala_tree.png&quot; alt=&quot;coala's tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see, this tree has 3 major parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;coalib&lt;/strong&gt;: Which is the homeground of coala API. This is the place where most of the important technical aspects goes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;docs&lt;/strong&gt;: Contains generated documention of coala API, which is built and beautifully displayed over &lt;a href=&quot;http://api.coala.io&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;api.coala.io&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tests&lt;/strong&gt;: Contains all the test files over coalib directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tests&lt;/code&gt; are established over &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coalib&lt;/code&gt;, so &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coalib&lt;/code&gt; is the star directory. And hence, I would be only explaining about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;coalib&quot;&gt;coalib&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coalib&lt;/code&gt; is the collection of various subpackages regarding writing, executing, editing bears, formatting, settings and much more. So let’s dig in boys!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coalib&lt;/code&gt; is further divided into 11 parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bearlib&lt;/strong&gt;: Which contains bear utilities, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aspects&lt;/code&gt;’s API, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;abstractions&lt;/code&gt; like linter bears and also &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;languages&lt;/code&gt; which contains various language definitions(such as identifying different languages with their versions) to provide unified language experience to coala.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bears&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides the base bear class i.e. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;LocalBear&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GlobalBear&lt;/code&gt;. Without which bears that exists in coala-bears &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coala/coala-bears&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt; wouldn’t exist.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;collecting&lt;/strong&gt;: provides collector routines which collects all bears, dependencies and file directories for coala. The collection works on the basis of 2 factors inputs provided at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/code&gt; and at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.coafile&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;core&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;core&lt;/code&gt; module contains the chronological order about what coala has to do with a bear. It takes care of all the step’s involved(like having a complete schedule), when a bear runs over a given file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;misc&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides all the other utilities like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cachingUtilities&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DictUtilities&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BuildManPage&lt;/code&gt; module and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Shell&lt;/code&gt; module. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Shell&lt;/code&gt; module is the important aspect here, as it helps coala to run in an interactive shell mode.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;output&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides the API for making coala interactive with its users via &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ConsoleInteraction&lt;/code&gt; module provides the utilities about user provided &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Actions&lt;/code&gt; like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Show_Patch&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Apply_Patch&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ignore_Patch&lt;/code&gt;..etc. It acts as a mediator between coala and the user, helps coala in providing the user important information by printing generated diff’s, messages, list of bears..etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;parsing&lt;/strong&gt;: The name itself suggests this is the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parsing&lt;/code&gt; module. It contains all the routines about parsing important information from a string of characters. Most of them support regex pattern matching. For example: Parsing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/code&gt; arguments and creating sections out of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;processes&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides the processing utilities and routines which takes decisive actions when a bear is in running state. It has routines which works like a control centre for processes. It takes care of process execution’s tasks such as:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;preparing a process -&amp;gt; loading files -&amp;gt; creating queues&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;spawn up one or more processes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;yielding results from the processes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;finally joining all the processes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;results&lt;/strong&gt;: This section works closely with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;output&lt;/code&gt; section. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;results&lt;/code&gt; provides routines like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Diff&lt;/code&gt; module, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;LineDiff&lt;/code&gt; module, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TextRange&lt;/code&gt; module and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ApplyAction&lt;/code&gt;’s module(user defined actions like ApplyPatch, IgnorePatch, ResultAction and ShowPatchAction). &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Diff&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;LineDiff&lt;/code&gt; modules are similar, they both generates a unified diff corresponding to a generated patch by coala. The only difference between them is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;LineDiff&lt;/code&gt; generates diffs over two strings wheareas &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Diff&lt;/code&gt; generates it over two files. When a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Diff&lt;/code&gt; is being generated or we have a yielded &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Result&lt;/code&gt;, it is supplied to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;output&lt;/code&gt; section, which in turn is being commuted to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;settings&lt;/strong&gt;: A &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setting&lt;/code&gt; in coala consists of a key and a value. It mainly offers many conversions into common data types. It provides important modules like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Section&lt;/code&gt; module which holds all the set of settings and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ConfigurationGathering&lt;/code&gt; module which plays two important roles:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;finds user configs(&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.coafile&lt;/code&gt; ofcourse)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;gathers configuration(such as loading configs, retrieves bears and all needed settings, saves the settings back if needed and warns about non existent targets)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;testing&lt;/strong&gt;: The last and final section is the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;testing&lt;/code&gt;, which contains the API for bear testing. It provides &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;LocalBearTestHelper&lt;/code&gt; module which contains routines like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;check_results&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;check_validity&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;verify_local_bear&lt;/code&gt;. These basically test a bear by doing a simple assertion test, between the given result and to the actual yielded result from the bear over a given file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you will dive deep enough, it’s working is even more interesting. If it sounds interesting to you as well, you can start contributing right away by following our &lt;a href=&quot;http://coala.io/newcomer&quot;&gt;newcomer’s guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till next time see ya!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/An-Insight-Into-coala's-Structure.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/An-Insight-Into-coala's-Structure.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>First Week GSoC'17</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey people!! This is the end of my first week at GSoC’2017 (Google Summer of Code). The programme kicks off with the start of community bonding. Which is probably the period where students and mentors break the ice between them. So, I will be summarizing what all has been done till now, and what lies on the road ahead. In this blog Im gonna explain about my project in little more detail, followed by my objective for the upcoming week. This is gonna be a lengthy one so hold on tight!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-my-project-about&quot;&gt;What’s my project about?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have already been through with the description of my project twice, in my previous blogs. So rather than repeating the same Im gonna explain you in a bit detail what exactly my project will be acheiving after it’s completion. So my project deals with the documentation of different languages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For java, the idea for the docstyle to be followed is defined &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/java/index-137868.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In general it will look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/**
 * &amp;lt;main_description&amp;gt;
 *
 * @param &amp;lt;param_name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;param_description&amp;gt;
 * @return             &amp;lt;return_description&amp;gt;
 */
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly for python, the idea for the docstring to be followed is defined in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0257/&quot;&gt;PEP-257&lt;/a&gt;. And this looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;
&amp;lt;main_description&amp;gt;

:param &amp;lt;param_name&amp;gt;:
    &amp;lt;param_description&amp;gt;
:return:
    &amp;lt;return_description&amp;gt;
&quot;&quot;&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I have to basically design an efficient API and later DocStyleBear &amp;amp; DocGrammarBear(using the API), which will contain analyzing routines over the documentation of python and java files according to the above defined format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-the-1st-week-go&quot;&gt;How did the 1st week go?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start of the week was full of joyness and excitement among all of the selected students. Which is because most of the bachelors (including me) are having first time experience as an intern and we are very much excited to begin our work. So we started our bonding period with a nice chat, setting everything up. Everything is going as smooth as it can ever be. We discussed about what all has to be done in the recent upcoming days, and what all will be done for the big picture. SO! LET’S ROLLLL!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first task was to create a detailed schedule over gitlab. We have done this through creating milestones according to official &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/open-source/gsoc/timeline&quot;&gt;GSoC Timeline&lt;/a&gt;. Which are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/4&quot;&gt;BONDING PERIOD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/5&quot;&gt;CODING PHASE-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/10&quot;&gt;CODING PHASE-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/coala/GSoC-2017/milestones/11&quot;&gt;CODING PHASE-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, was to introduce myself to the whole community on the coala-dev &amp;amp; coala-newcomers mailing lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Final, was that I have get my feed.xml for this blog-page to be aggregated with &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.coala.io/&quot;&gt;blog.coala.io&lt;/a&gt;. You guys can now also access my blogs @coala’s official &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.coala.io/&quot;&gt;blog-page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-for-the-upcoming-week&quot;&gt;What’s for the upcoming week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally my exams are over and summer vacation has begun. Now I can devote my full time to this project. So probably Im gonna start completing my BONDING PERIOD: Milestones. Which right now has 4 issues. Also, I will be diving deep into the coala’s codebase to understand its voodoo, and will be writing about it’s working in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it for this week folks!! See yaa!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/First-Week-GSoC'17.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/First-Week-GSoC'17.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Accepted YAY!</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The day for which I had waited so long has finally come. My project with coala has been accepted. Hooray!!! This probably is my biggest life achievement so far and I’m so happy from inside that there are butterflies fluttering in my stomach :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/gsoc_mail.png&quot; alt=&quot;GSoC Mail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project I got accepted is named as Documentation Extraction and Parsing. This project is all about developing an analyzing routine at least for python and java that will find all documentation strings in a file, parse them into specific groups and check them against a specified documentation style given by the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now the period is called Community Bonding, and lasts until 30th of May, after which the actual work starts. This is the time when students and mentors get to know each other and talk about implementing the project. Also play a bit of factorio together :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-going-to-be-hard&quot;&gt;It’s going to be hard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now I was only working on college projects and came onto open-source projects from last october. wheareas I started with coala in January’s end. This was the hardest time I had spent in the entire course of my engineering and was incredibly fruitful. I feel like this project is going to be a real-challenge, to which I m planning to work hard on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month will be a challenge to me as I have my ongoing final exams till 16th of May. Yes, it’s going to be hell hard. But nothing comes easy on your plate, does it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thanks-people&quot;&gt;Thanks! people!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post was intended to thank everyone involved. Special thanks goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SanketDG&quot;&gt;Sanket Dasgupta&lt;/a&gt; and other mentors from coala. Also credit is all yours &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vVv-AA&quot;&gt;Jasmin Patel&lt;/a&gt; for encouraging me in the initial phase :) With the help of these amazing people, I was able to achieve something I never thought I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every weekend from now onwards I will write about my ongoing work. Till my next post See yaa!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/Accepted_YAY!.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/Accepted_YAY!.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>My Project Proposals</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since my last blog. So, this blog is all about my goals towards this year’s awesome summer. Let’s directly come to the point. Guys, I’m participating in Google Summer of Code 2017 (GSoC-2017). I will tell you more about my proposals, meanwhile lets get familiar with some pre-requisites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-gsoc-is-about&quot;&gt;What GSoC is about?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Summer of Code, often abbreviated to GSoC, is an international annual program, in which Google awards stipends, to all students who successfully complete a requested free and open-source software coding project during the summer. It is focused on bringing more student developers into open source software development. Students work with an open source organization on a 3 month programming project during their break from college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-project-proposals&quot;&gt;My Project Proposals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/my_proposal.png&quot; alt=&quot;My Project Proposals&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, The student application window is open. And Im really excited about participating in it. So here’s the deal. Im applying for 2 project proposals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation Extraction and Parsing&lt;/strong&gt;: Well this project is all about developing an analyzing routine at least for python and java that will find all documentation strings in a file, parse them into specific groups and check them against a specified documentation style given by the user. For more specific info look at my &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B2ZlhOHwaV58Tmhva09ua3FRNzQ&quot;&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle Nested Programming Language&lt;/strong&gt;: This one will help coala and its users by having analyzing routines over nested languages (eg. a html file can have php in it, such as inside a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;code-block&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;). For more specific info look at my &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B2ZlhOHwaV58YW5acDJKLWkxMDA&quot;&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it guys!! I will be writting my next blog ahh not soon enough :( busy in projects and assignments, but you can surely expect one after the results of GSoC 2017 being declared. Till then see yaa next time :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/gsoc/My-Project-Proposals.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gsoc/My-Project-Proposals.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The 3 Things I Learned</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello people, So it’s been a week and as promised, I’m going to tell you about my experience in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coala&lt;/code&gt;. Which is an open-source community. I will specifically tell you about my journey, and probably everything that happened to me in the first two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-coala-is-about&quot;&gt;What coala is about?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coala&lt;/code&gt; written with small &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;c&lt;/code&gt;, stands for “COde AnaLysis Application”. As it’s name suggests, coala is a static code analysis software that empowers developers to create rules which a project’s code should conform to. coala takes care of showing these issues to users in a friendly manner, is versatile and can be used in any environment. It also show’s Patches in a friendly manner which can fix your code according to the specified rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-i-chose-coala-for-open-source-contribution&quot;&gt;Why I chose coala for open-source contribution?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is very simple, it’s written in python. And out of the blue box this project came to me while I was surfing on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-my-first-2-weeks-after-joining-the-community&quot;&gt;About my first 2 weeks after joining the community.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we have a newcomers guide, which every newcomer has to follow. The very first step in the guide was to introduce yourself on the gitter channel. We have a secret code-word for all newcomers, “Hello World”. So I just pinged on the channel and soon I got an invitation to the organisation. The guide is very helpful towards newcomers. It’s a complete guide which will land you to get your first Pull Request(PR) merged. The newcomers issues are very simple. Can vary from correcting a typo, removing a line or fixing some simple stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This community has a workflow that on each issue only an individual who is assigned to it, can work for it. So my first task was to get myself assigned to a newcomer’s issue. Well in coala most of the things are automated. So, for issue assignment we have a gitter &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cobot&lt;/code&gt; (coala bot) with which you can easily assign yourself to any issue with a single command. Soon after I got myself assigned to one, I started working on my first patch. It was about removing deprecated &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;center&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags from their “projects” website. Well that was pretty easy isn’t it? Yes, so I finished making my PR in about 10-15 mins. Just Wait a sec! the work doesn’t get’s over yet!!. We have some specific rules before a PR is merged into the code-base. After submitting your PR you have to wait for a review from any existing member of a community. Which I feel is the best thing in this community, anyone can review anyone’s PR. By reviewing we can even learn more about someone’s work. This even embraces our own coding knowledge. I totally love reviewing other’s work by this you can actually learn more about coding style. So, soon my pending PR got reviewed and BAAM! in 2 days my first patch got merged into coala’s code-base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this I took 2-3 more issues. And on the end of my second week I got promoted to a core-dev &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coala.io/&quot;&gt;@coala&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/developer_result.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Developer Result&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the maintainer’s and my fellow dev’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coala.io/&quot;&gt;@coala&lt;/a&gt;. Special Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sils&quot;&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Makman2&quot;&gt;@Makman2&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jayvdb&quot;&gt;@jayvdb&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SanketDG&quot;&gt;@SanketDG&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Mixih&quot;&gt;@mixih&lt;/a&gt; for giving me an initial boost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-3-things-i-learned&quot;&gt;The 3 Things I Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first and the most exciting thing I learned after joining coala was, getting to know people and about their work. It’s really fascinating how much these people invest their time in open-source project. And at last it’s all worth it. Every single bit of it. I can actually tell you that, after experiencing it myself. The feel about how your work can make a difference in million’s of peoples lives, is enough to get yourself motivated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Second thing I learned was, whenever you got yourself stuck at some point while working on an issue. Don’t directly ask for it in the channel without doing some prior research on it. In my opinion this actually wastes a lot of time even for you and also for the person who is answering it. Doing some prior research can actually help you to support your case well, you can elaborate the cause well by saying that, “I have tried these all things but still this isn’t working for me”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third and the last thing which I learned was about reviewing. Doing patches solving issues, isn’t the only way to contribute in an organisation. Reviewing is also one of the most important aspect. By reviewing you can actually learn about how a code can be written in more than one way. Sometimes, you can even get you hands on small tricks, when applied can actually make your code much more efficient than before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this was all about my first few weeks experience in coala. For more, Stay Tuned! And Start Contributing :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/journal/The-3-Things-I-Learned.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/journal/The-3-Things-I-Learned.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Road Ahead!</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, people. So this is probably my first blog ever! And, I will be writing here about all the cool stuff on which I’m working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-road-ahead&quot;&gt;A Road Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the name itself justifies I’m going on a road, a journey. Any Guesses? Well, My journey has already begun in the last week of January 2017. And it’s about joining an open-source community. So, it has been 3 weeks for me and in this blog I will be explaining about how anyone can start contributing to an open-source environment. By giving a gist of my experience I hope you will also make your mind in taking your first step towards the open-source world. But first we need some prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-an-open-source-anyway-&quot;&gt;What’s an open-source anyway ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a simple way, open-source Applications/Softwares are free softwares for which the original source code is made freely available and may be redistributed and modified. So, anyone can use open-source software for free, for forever…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-should-i-do-open-source-contribution-&quot;&gt;Why should I do open-source contribution ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to me to learn any specific language suppose &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C Language&lt;/code&gt;. The best way to dive into something is to do a project on it. That’s why I suggest you to join open-source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, talkin about my experience when my first ever patch got merged into main code-base. The, feeling which I got was immensely great. It wasn’t about “my patch got accepted yay!” But the feeling was more about ,”Now my patch will help million’s of world wide user’s. They will be using my work in their daily life”. And at the end it will be worth while your time. I can surely asure you that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;which-open-source-project-should-i-choose-how-can-i-get-started-&quot;&gt;Which open-source project should I choose? How can I get started ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is trivial. I really think that one should always follow his instincts. So, go ahead choose what interests you the most. There are many great projects but I would personally recommend you to start working on small projects then go towards big sheeps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-i-need-any-prerequisites-&quot;&gt;Do I need any prerequisites ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That depend’s on how you want to work on the project. You can either hack the core of the language first or directly go on with the flow. The second option is mostly choosed over the first. Even I’m learning with the flow!!, but contributing towards open-source projects requires hell lot of a patience. Which I think once you get started, you will get a hang of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, those are the most basic questions which I find people asking around. And now I will be sharing with you, which open-source project I have choosen and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all started when I came across python in the 1st week of january 2017. And I found it very interesting towards it’s simplicity, working with lists, so many ready-mate packages, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NumPy&lt;/code&gt; which made N-dimentional array object’s a child’s play and so-on. So, I decided to choose this language, and wanted to do a project on it. Literally I knew nothing about which project I’m gonna choose? So out of the blue box while surfing on the internet, I came across this wonderful project called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coala&lt;/code&gt;, which basically does static code-analysis. This project in itself is very awesome. I would like to tell you more about it! But you have to wait till next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it folks! Hope you like my first blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/journal/A-Road-Ahead.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/journal/A-Road-Ahead.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
